<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-30T21:20:39-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">June 2020 Roundup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/29/june-2020-roundup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="June 2020 Roundup" /><published>2020-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/29/june-2020-roundup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/29/june-2020-roundup.html">&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;section section-books&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/div&gt;
   
    &lt;div class=&quot;section-content&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; data-aos=&quot;fade-in&quot; data-aos-offset=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h5 class=&quot;bold item-title&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Educated&lt;/span&gt; by Tara Westover
          (3.5 / 5)
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35133922-educated&quot;&gt;
          [goodreads]
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/h5&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;
          &lt;div class=item-image&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          A highly popular autobiography of Tara Westover’s childhood as the youngest 
          of seven children in a survivalist Mormon family in Idaho, with parents who 
          largely shunned hospitals, formal education, and society at large. It spans 
          her early childhood with her siblings helping her mother, an herbalist and 
          midwife, and father, who worked in a junkyard. As a child she and her 
          siblings were exposed to their father’s extreme fundamentalist Mormon 
          doctrine, and also to highly dangerous conditions while aiding their 
          father’s business. The book details the physical and psychological abuse 
          Tara and her siblings faced from her elder brother Shawn (a pseudonym), 
          and the tearing apart of her family that this abuse resulted in. Tara, 
          following the example of her brother Tyler, miraculously self-studies well 
          enough in the span of a couple years to propel herself into BYU, then 
          Cambridge.
          &lt;/br&gt;
          There are some aspects of the book that I find hard to believe. Her 
          parents are difficult figures to understand, at times loving and supportive 
          of college, but generally painted in broad and unsympathetic strokes 
          (understandably, given the tension between Tara and her parents). Like 
          others, I do suspect some elements of Tara’s quick propulsion to education 
          to be exaggerated, although it is not really my place to judge.
          &lt;/br&gt;
          Overall, I can see why the book was a quick and dramatic crowd-pleaser, and
          it depicted a successful image of physical and psychological abuse. I just 
          think that other parts of the book should be taken with a grain of salt.
        &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--close item--&gt;

      &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; data-aos=&quot;fade-in&quot; data-aos-offset=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h5 class=&quot;bold item-title&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;The Yellow House&lt;/span&gt; by Sarah M Broom
          (4/5)
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43347603-the-yellow-house&quot;&gt;
            [goodreads]
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/h5&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;
         This book is a well written, highly personal memoir of a house and its 
         family, and the winner of the 2019 National Book Award for Nonfiction. 
         It is quite deserving of that title. The Yellow House, located in New Orleans East,
         was purchased by Ivory Mae, the author Sarah's mother, where she eventually 
         raised a total of 12 children. 
         &lt;/br&gt;
         This is a social history of how the house centered this family, and how the Water 
         (Hurricane Katrina) scattered its members. It deals with the relations of 
         New Orleans East to the rest of the city, the right to ownership of a place 
         and a house, the meaning of such ownership, and the act of trying to 
         remember from a past that was collectively but not personally experienced.
         Sarah writes of the efforts she goes through to piece together her father,
         who died shortly after she was born. She ponders over the push-and-pull
         relationship she and her family feel towards New Orleans, particularly 
         after the Water; her quest to find her roots and takes her to Burundi and to
         the French Quarter, the touristy part of the city.
         &lt;div class=&quot;block-quote&quot;&gt;
          Who has the rights to the story of a place? Are these rights earned, 
          bought, fought and died for? Or are they given? Are they automatic, like 
          an assumption? Self-renewing? Are these rights a token of citizenship 
          belonging to those who stay in the place or to those who leave and come 
          back to it? Does the act of leaving relinquish one’s rights to the story 
          of a place? Who stays gone? Who can afford to return?
         &lt;/div&gt;
         The book successfully broaches themes of inequality and internalized shame. 
         Sarah comments on the history of New Orleans and its relationship with 
         New Orleans East, the predominantly black and working-class suburb of the 
         city, and how the city dealt with its people after the hurricane.
         &lt;/br&gt;
         There are so many things to love about this memoir. It can be a slower
         read for those who have no investment in or relation to New Orleans, but 
         is still worth a read nonetheless.
         To me, the best parts of the story were those spent with the members of
         Broom's family, who were so intimately and colorfully described. 
        &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- close section-content --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- close item --&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- close section-books --&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;section section-music&quot;&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- close section-music --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="favorites" /><category term="books" /><summary type="html">Books Educated by Tara Westover (3.5 / 5) [goodreads] A highly popular autobiography of Tara Westover’s childhood as the youngest of seven children in a survivalist Mormon family in Idaho, with parents who largely shunned hospitals, formal education, and society at large. It spans her early childhood with her siblings helping her mother, an herbalist and midwife, and father, who worked in a junkyard. As a child she and her siblings were exposed to their father’s extreme fundamentalist Mormon doctrine, and also to highly dangerous conditions while aiding their father’s business. The book details the physical and psychological abuse Tara and her siblings faced from her elder brother Shawn (a pseudonym), and the tearing apart of her family that this abuse resulted in. Tara, following the example of her brother Tyler, miraculously self-studies well enough in the span of a couple years to propel herself into BYU, then Cambridge. There are some aspects of the book that I find hard to believe. Her parents are difficult figures to understand, at times loving and supportive of college, but generally painted in broad and unsympathetic strokes (understandably, given the tension between Tara and her parents). Like others, I do suspect some elements of Tara’s quick propulsion to education to be exaggerated, although it is not really my place to judge. Overall, I can see why the book was a quick and dramatic crowd-pleaser, and it depicted a successful image of physical and psychological abuse. I just think that other parts of the book should be taken with a grain of salt.</summary></entry></feed>